<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zhengyi Liang on To be a computational social scientist</title>
    <link>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zhengyi Liang on To be a computational social scientist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 20:57:06 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Geometry of Culture by Doc2vec</title>
      <link>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/project/doc2vec/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 20:57:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/project/doc2vec/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I crawled data from a website and sucessfully retrieved approximately 290,000 Chinese book summaries. I applied a neural-network word embedding model to discover the culture dimensions hidden under the large-scale book summaries.The idea was inspired by the paper The Geometry of Culture: Analyzing Meaning through Word Embeddings, which corroborated the effectiveness of the new methodological tool word embedding by constructing different cultural dimensions.
First of all, due to the different sentence structure between Chinese and English, it was essential to seperate Chinese and remove stopwords before training the model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to expedite the process of data crawling?</title>
      <link>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/computation/crawle_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/computation/crawle_data/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I crawled a set of users&amp;rsquo; book collections from an online community. First I randomly generated about 1 million user ids and obtained book collections by iterating the search. Because some user ids were invalid, over 110,000 users’ book collections were acquired eventually. To crawl a large dataset, web crawlers have to confront a major challenge, that is how to expedite the process since most websites designed Anti-crawlers tactics to obstruct crawling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Machine Learning: the Key to Unthinkable Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/post/workshop_machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/post/workshop_machine/</guid>
      <description>As Richard Hamming said, “just as there are odours that dogs can smell and we cannot, as well as sounds that dogs can hear and we cannot&amp;hellip;Perhaps there are thoughts we cannot think. Evolution, so far, may possibly have blocked us from being able to think in some directions, there could be unthinkable thoughts.’’ Machine is probably the extension of human brain, which is the key to unthinkable thoughts.
I participated in a workshop about machine learning in Nanjing University in January, 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review of Bit by Bit: social research in the digital age</title>
      <link>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/post/book_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/post/book_review/</guid>
      <description>Bit by Bit: social research in the digital age is written by Matthew Salganik, a professor of Princeton University, who has great interests in computational social science. Computational social science is a brand-new research filed without many guidelines or principles. This book is perhaps the first “textbook” in the field. Based on the book, I would like to share some thoughts with regards to datasets and methods in the digital age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replication of the Spread of True and False News Online </title>
      <link>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/computation/code_replication/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/computation/code_replication/</guid>
      <description>According to the data and code shared by the researchers, I replicate the results of the study.
Access to the paper:http://science.sciencemag.org/content/359/6380/1146
Author Soroush Vosoughi, Deb Roy, Sinan Aral
Central Findings They found that false news was more novel than true news, which suggests that people were more likely to share novel information. Whereas false stories inspired fear, disgust, and surprise in replies, true stories inspired anticipation, sadness, joy, and trust.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>