<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Uncover the Unknown</title>
    <link>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Uncover the Unknown</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Smokeless Battle: Confronting the Spread of Coronavirus Outbreak Worldwide</title>
      <link>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/project/virus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 19:00:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/project/virus/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The epidemic has touched all the continents that humans inhabit within several months. This project seeks to track the spread of the outbreak in different areas and the movement of disease hotspots. Besides, the paper also delineates the overall situation in China, where the government took sweeping measures against the greatest outbreak and proposes an indicator, intervention efficacy to assess the effectiveness of government intervention in containing the virus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constructing Ideological Space: Estimating Political Attitudes through Chinese People’s Consumption of Books </title>
      <link>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/project/ideological_space/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 13:22:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/project/ideological_space/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Ideology has been a focus issue in the domain of political science. Researchers have long depended on a survey to measure political attitudes, but the method is expensive and limited to time and space. Hence, a great many studies took an unconventional approach to quantify ideology based on discrete behavioral data, including roll-call votes and social media’s endorsement, and generated reliable outcomes. This study contributed to that promising research avenue by estimating ideology through people’s reading patterns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does economic openness create more liberal readers in China?</title>
      <link>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/project/readers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 10:38:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/project/readers/</guid>
      <description>A growing body of research has explored the ideological differences in reading. Shi and colleagues (2017) found the partisan distinctiveness in the consumption of science books. Consumers for liberal political books favor basic science, while conservative consumers prefer applied and commercial science. Hoffman examined the political nature of reading and revealed that the reading preference became polarized over time between Federalists and Democratic-Republicans in American elite society in the 18th century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Popularity determines how Chinese netizens select a political book rather than political alignment</title>
      <link>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/project/polarization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 10:38:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/project/polarization/</guid>
      <description>Political Polarization in China? Political polarization is one of the most heatedly discussed issues in America. A great number of research papers delve into the topic. Recently, I have been exploring large-scale political books data derived from an online reading community. The data is composed of users’ book collections (When a user takes an interest in a book, she/he tags it). When I was probing into the data, one question struck me: is there political polarization in China?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Geometry of Culture: How Chinese perceive and apprehend politics</title>
      <link>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/project/doc2vec/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 20:57:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/project/doc2vec/</guid>
      <description>Research Question How do Chinese perceive and apprehend politics?
Methodology A public-available word embedding dataset trained by the Word2vec/skip gram algorithm is obtained to examine political connotations. The word embedding model is appropriate to represent political associations based on three reasons. First, it was trained by a large corpus covering various subjects, such as People&amp;rsquo;s Daily News, Baidu Encyclopedia, Weibo (equivalent of Tweeter) and literature. Specifically, the corpus encompasses political coverage on the news outlets and political discussions on social media, which enables the embedding model to capture underlying political connotations among words.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>