<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Explore the Unknown</title>
    <link>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Explore the Unknown</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Popularity determines how Chinese netizens select a political book rather than political alignment</title>
      <link>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/project/polarization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 10:38:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/project/polarization/</guid>
      <description>Political Polarization in China? Political polarization is one of the most heatedly discussed issues in America. A great number of research papers delve into the topic. Recently, I have been exploring large-scale political books data derived from an online reading community. The data is composed of users’ book collections (When a user takes an interest in a book, she/he tags it). When I was probing into the data, one question struck me: is there political polarization in China?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Geometry of Culture: How Chinese perceive and apprehend politics</title>
      <link>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/project/doc2vec/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 20:57:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/project/doc2vec/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I crawled data from a website and successfully obtained approximately 290,000 Chinese book summaries. I employed a neural-network word embedding model to discover the culture dimensions hidden under the large-scale book summaries. The idea was inspired by the paper The Geometry of Culture: Analyzing Meaning through Word Embeddings, which corroborated the effectiveness of the new methodological tool word embedding by constructing different cultural dimensions.
Figure 1: The Distance between Words in a Sky Map</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>