<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computation on Thinking the Unthinkable</title>
    <link>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/computation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computation on Thinking the Unthinkable</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/computation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to expedite the process of data crawling?</title>
      <link>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/computation/crawle_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/computation/crawle_data/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I crawled a set of users&amp;rsquo; book collections from an online community. First I randomly generated about 1 million user ids and obtained book collections by iterating the search. Because some user ids were invalid, over 110,000 users’ book collections were acquired eventually. To crawl a large dataset, web crawlers have to confront a major challenge, which is how to expedite the process since most websites designed Anti-crawlers tactics to obstruct crawling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replication of the Spread of True and False News Online </title>
      <link>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/computation/code_replication/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liangzhengyiyi.github.io/computation/code_replication/</guid>
      <description>According to the data and code shared by the researchers, I replicate the results of the study.
Access to the paper:http://science.sciencemag.org/content/359/6380/1146
Author Soroush Vosoughi, Deb Roy, Sinan Aral
Central Findings They found that false news was more novel than true news, which suggests that people were more likely to share novel information. Whereas false stories inspired fear, disgust, and surprise in replies, true stories inspired anticipation, sadness, joy, and trust.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>